# Vamsi Ravilisetti

🤳 8247825974 | 🖾 vamsi995141@gmail.com | 🛅 <u>Vamsi Ravilisetti</u> | 🖶 <u>Portfolio</u> | ♥ Hyderabad, India

#### **SUMMARY**

Fast-paced, creative web developer with 2.5 years of experience with extensive knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular 12/13/14/15/16,Bootstrap, Node.js, SCSS, Angular Material and other web programming languages. Strong proficiency in visual design, user interface design and APIs integration.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Aditya College of Engineering**

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering

Jun. 2017 – Aug 2021 Suramplem, IND

## **SKILLS**

Angular, JavaScript, Typescript(Angular), HTML, CSS, GraphQI, SQL (MySQL), DSA(Data Structures and Algorithms), python, java, Bootstrap, Jira, Material, GitHub, MongoDB, NVM, Tailwind CSS, Nx Console, Rxjs, Node.js, Micro-Front end, PWA(Progressive Wen Applications).

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Knoxpo Solutions**Sep. 2023 – Present *Angular Developer*Surat, IND

ngular Developer Surat, INC

- Led front-end development of a EKYC project from built scratch using Angular with Micro-front end architecture.
  Developed and maintained Angular applications resulting in increased increased efficiency by 20% in 3 months.
- Implemented responsive design using HTML and CSS resulting in 15% increase in user engagement.
- Coordinated with the architecture group to define the technical platform resulting in a 20% increase in system reliability.

LTIMindtree Sep. 2021 – Aug. 2023

Software Engineer

Hyderabad, IND

- Developed and deployed Angular Applications resulting in a 30% increase in client satisfaction
- Improved application performance by 23% through code optimization and refactoring.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to deliver projects on time within budget.
- Developed and maintained websites resulting in a 40% increase in traffic.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Knoxpo EKYC Project**

E-KYC or electronic Know Your Customer is essentially the process by which KYC is done. So, eKYC is when authorised organisations and agents verify a customer's identity and address digitally

- Coordinated team for successful development of project
- Developed the EKYC project from scratch with Angular 16 using Nx Console Micro front-end with efficiency.
- Created custom reusable libraries to improve efficiency of web application
- implemented Micro-front end architecture in angular web application
- Led team of 4 developers to complete a project ahead of schedule.
- Collaborated with the graphic designer and HTML coder to ensure a clear dependency chain, resulting in a 20% reduction in development time and a 10% increase in overall code quality

## Connect 365 Automated Email campaign project

Connect 365 is a client attraction and sales automation platform that provides simple solutions to help small and medium sized businesses start more sales conversations with qualified prospects every day of the year while eliminating 90% of their marketing workload.

- Provided support to customer in project development and support.
- Developed Several Modules in the project which contributed in the successful deployment of project within time.
- Communicated with external web services to integrate payment gateways and shipping providers, resulting in a seamless checkout process and a 25% increase in customer satisfaction.
- · Connect 365 URL

# L & T Electrical Smartshopt

L & T Electrical Smart shop is an e-commerce project in collaboration with Schneider Electric where all the electrical products user can buy. This project will be going to be operational in India and European countries.

- Developed several modules and maintain collaboration with Back-end and Design team.
- Developed and implemented a new Angular-based e-commerce platform, resulting in a **35% increase in sales and a 20% increase** in customer retention.
- Involved in Integrating the Graph QL APIs.
- Implemented PWA(progressive web application) feature in Angular Wen Application
- · Integrated payment gateway for online purchase using Razorpay.
- Collaborated with the back-end development team to build a RESTful API, improving the overall performance of the
  application and reducing load times by30%.

## **LANGUAGES**

English, Hindi, Telugu

## **Declaration**

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.